HUW JONES

User-centred digital product designer/developer

A PROFILE:

I'm a designer/developer with over 20 years' experience in digital media. I'm looking to use my background in psychology, ui development experience and freshly honed UX design skills to help create digital products that educate, inform and empower users.

EXPERIENCE:

Digital Learning Producer

WJEC/CBAC, Cardiff, Wales, Oct 2015 - Mar 2023

- Responsible for the production of bilingual (English and Welsh) digital and print classroom resources, to be used by students and front-of-class.
- Took ownership of projects' development and collaborated with stakeholders to ensure projects were completed to a high standard and met tight deadlines.
- Increased the efficiency of Figma prototype production in the team by cataloguing all available component variations and standardising the structure of the component library.
- Expanded my area of expertise into user-centred design, taking numerous UX, UI and Design thinking courses with the Interaction Design Foundation. Recently been informed by IDF that I am in the top 1% of students globally.
- Development team's self-imposed lead on accessibility issues, looking for ways to include best practice in production processes resulting in more inclusive resources.

Teacher Guidance Team Leader

WJEC/CBAC, Cardiff, Wales, May 2015 - Oct 2015

- Responsible for the creation of the Teacher Guidance resources for the new A level and GCSE specifications.
- Increased design cohesion, clarity and focus by modularising content to make the resources more usable and less repetitive.
- Duties included overall management of the project and the workload of seconded members of staff.

Educational Resources Developer

WJEC/CBAC, Cardiff, Wales, Jan 2011 - May 2015

- Worked as part of a small team producing bilingual (English and Welsh) flash-based classroom resources.
- Active member of the company's 'web group' that would meet to inform WJEC's online strategy and determine how best to implement the future roadmap.

huw.jones79@gmail.com

& 07415 414 926

in huw-jones-designer

www.huwx.net

今 SKILLS:

- · Front end development
- UI design
- · Design thinking
- UX design
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Design system management
- User scenario testing
- · Competitor analysis
- Heuristic analysis

</> DEVELOPMENT:

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Sass
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React
- · Redux toolkit
- · React testing kit
- JEST
- jQuery

e-Assessment Developer

WJEC/CBAC, Cardiff, Wales, Nov 2007 - Jan 2011

- Produced high-stakes, summative, on-screen assessments.
- Responsible for training colleagues and stakeholders in the use of specialist assessment authoring software.
- Regularly lead the discussions with external technology partners, BTL, with regard to technical question-creation issues.

New Platforms Producer

Red Dragon FM, Cardiff, Wales, Aug 2006 - Apr 2007

- Responsible for meeting the interactive needs of the radio station, including the website content and podcast production.
- Monitored user analytics for the Red Dragon FM website

 insights and knowledge of user-engagement helped
 the team drive total market share from 11.9% to 15.3% in an increasingly competitive market.

Founder and Media Designer

Siliconspider Design, RCT, Wales, Dec 2000 - Aug 2004

- Freelance web and print designer accountable for all stages of development - from making initial pitches to prospective clients, to presenting final deliverables and justifying my design decisions.
- Advised clients on content structure and user task flow for websites, often producing basic wireframes and sitemaps.

PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT:

UI design patterns for successful software Interaction Design Foundation

User experience: the beginner's guide Interaction Design Foundation

Design thinking: a beginner's guide Interaction Design Foundation

Conducting Usability testing Interaction Design Foundation

Management Development Centre WJEC internal course

Stepping into Management WJEC internal course

Coaching and Mentoring

WJEC internal course



PG Dip Interactive Media

University of Wales, Lampeter (2005-06)

PG Cert Graphic Communication

The University of Glamorgan (2004-05)

BTEC Foundation Studies: Art and Design.

Glamorgan Centre for Art and Design Technology (2003-04)

City & Guilds: Design & Craft (level 2) including life drawing

Glamorgan Centre for Art and Design Technology (2003-04)

BSc (Hons) Psychology City University, London EC1 (1996-99)

□ LANGUAGES:

- · Fluent Welsh speaker
- Conversational French